

#### CONTACT

Manchester/Leeds

**390987 390987** 

james-collins.netlify.app

github.com/jimwcollins

(in) linkedin.com/in/jimwcollins

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### General

- App development
- Website development
- Object-oriented / functional programming
- RESTful API development

# Languages

- TypeScript
- Node.js / JavaScript
- C# (including Ling)

# Front end

- React
- React Native
- React Navigation
- Redux / Redux Persist
- React Router/ React Query
- Tailwind / Styled Components
- O HTML 5 / CSS 3
- SCSS / Sass

# Back end

- Amazon Web Services
- Google Firebase
- Supabase
- Relational Databases / SQL

# **Testing**

- Integration and unit testing with Jest
- E2E testing with Detox
- Test Driven Development

# **JAMES COLLINS**

# **DEVELOPER • DESIGNER**

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a full-stack developer and graphic designer, and throughout my career I've been guided by these twin passions. I've loved coding since I was a boy writing text adventures in BASIC, and have always enjoyed the unique mix of creativity and problem-solving it requires. I have a degree in Computer Science, and I am a graduate of Northcoders coding bootcamp. I have also completed the BCS Level 4 Software Developer apprenticeship.

I am currently a software developer at Tred, where I have gained over three years' experience in full-stack app development.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### FULL-STACK DEVELOPER • Tred

June 2021 - Present

- Tred are a pioneering green fintech, helping businesses track their spending and carbon footprint through a debit card and mobile app.
- On the front-end, I work with React Native and TypeScript, building and maintaining our mobile app for both iOS and Android.
- I also use Google Firebase to handle push notifications and remote
  app configuration.
- O I am also part of Tred's design team, leveraging my understanding of strong UX/UI to produce an app that is attractive and user-friendly.
- I use Figma to produce designs and prototypes, and am also in the process of adding animations to the app via Rive and React Native Reanimated.
- On the back-end, I work with Node.js and TypeScript, building a serverless solution on the AWS platform. We use TypeORM for database management, and deploy via the Serverless framework.
- We follow an Agile, sprint-based approach, utilising industry bestpractices including Git, Jira ticket management, regular code reviews, daily stand-ups and pair programming.
- O Visit: www.tred.earth

# BCS LEVEL 4 SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT • Northcoders

August 2021 - April 2023

- Whilst at Tred, I completed a BCS software development apprenticeship with Northcoders.
- Software and mobile app development with C# and JavaScript, AWS,
  Detox, deployment to AWS via Terraform, and relational databases.
- We also covered the SDLC, SOLID principles, testing frameworks and software design patterns.

# **DESIGN SKILLS**

- UX/UI design
- App, web and print design
- Image editing/retouching
- Typography
- Adobe Creative Suite (InDesign, Photoshop, Illustrator, After Effects)
- Figma

### **EDUCATION**

# **NCTJ JOURNALISM** Harlow Journalism Centre

January 2003 - July 2003

- A journalism course with a focus on magazines.
- Covered design, subediting, photography, feature writing.

# **BSc COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Nottingham**

**September 1996 - June 1999** 

- Object-oriented and functional programming, user interface design, software architecture and databases.
- Languages included Java, C++, HTML and SQL.

# **3 A-LEVELS • 10 GCSES** Quinton House, Northampton 1992 - 1996

- A-levels in mathematics, physics and English.
- GCSEs including maths, science, I.T. and electronics.

## **INTERESTS**







Design

Music

Gaming





Travel

Photography Cycling







# **EXPERIENCE** CONTINUED

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

February 2021 - May 2021

0 I continued to expand my skills in React and JavaScript through online courses and personal projects.

# **GRADUATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER • Northcoders**

September 2020 - January 2021

0 A challenging programme teaching full-stack software development using technologies including JavaScript, React, Axios, Express.js and SQL.

#### 0 Northcoders project: Meme What You Say

- · A real-time, multiplayer iOS caption game built with React Native and a Google Firebase non-relational database.
- Visit: james-collins.netlify.app/pages/projects/meme.html
- GitHub: github.com/jimwcollins/meme-game

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

January 2020 - August 2020

0 I challenged myself to relearn web development, completing online courses in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and motion graphics.

#### Personal project: Portfolio website 0

- Built with HTML, CSS, Flexbox, CSS grids and JavaScript.
- Visit: james-collins.netlify.app
- GitHub: github.com/jimwcollins/portfolio
- 0 I also fulfilled a lifelong dream and completed my first novel.

# **FREELANCE DESIGN**

September 2007 - December 2019

- 0 Sole responsibility for the complete design cycle, from initial concept and design through to layout and the production of print PDFs.
- 0 Extensive use of Photoshop to manipulate/retouch images.
- Close collaboration with clients. 0

# **DESIGNER** • Think Publishing

October 2003 - August 2007

- 0 Design of magazines, books and advertisements.
- Working individually and in collaboration with the design, editorial 0 and advertising sales teams.

## **WEBSITE DEVELOPER • Quidnunc**

September 1999 - September 2002

- 0 Key team member developing websites and applications for clients including M&S and the University of Cambridge.
- 0 I was also a member of the client technical support team, dealing with challenging and often time-critical issues.